Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
1809-2017
RG 279
Yale University Divinity School Library
47
(113 boxes)
This collection contains publications by faculty of Andover Newton Theological School and its predecessors, Andover Theological Seminary and the Newton Theological Institution. These writings were gathered into the collection in order to provide a consolidated repository for the works of Andover Newton faculty.
Biographical / Historical
Andover Theological Seminary was founded in 1807. The origin of the school can be traced to Phillips Academy, which was established in 1778 at Andover, Massachusetts. Specific instruction in divinity was provided in 1794 when a legacy was received for the support of a professor of divinity. In 1807, additional funds made possible the founding of a separate department of divinity. The following year, the theological institution known as Andover Theological Seminary was opened for instruction. In 1907 the Seminary transferred to Harvard University. In 1931 the Seminary transferred to Newton Centre, and became affiliated with Newton Theological Institution to form Andover Newton Theological School. In 1965 the two schools formally merged.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Andover Newton Theological School, 2017
Scope and Contents
This collection contains publications by faculty members who taught at Andover Newton Theological School and its predecessor institutions, Andover Theological Seminary and the Newton Theological Institution. Unpublished writings by these faculty members may be available with their personal papers.
Universities and colleges -- Faculty; Andover Newton Theological School
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Adams, James Luther
    - "The Liberalism that is Dead." Journal of Liberal Religion (Winter 1940):. (mimeograph copy, with annotation and note "On Being HumanC pp. 4-11.) (Box 1)
    - "Frontiers of Freedom." From Radio Broadcast over the NBC Blue Network, Oct. 26, 1941, by JLA and Kenneth Leslie (mimeographed from pamphlet.) (Box 1)
    - "Frontiers of Freedom." From Radio Broadcast over the NBC Blue Network, Oct. 26, 1941, by JLA and Kenneth Leslie (Box 1)
    - "The Religious Problem." Reprinted for private circulation from George B. Huszar, editor, New Perspectives on Peace. Chicago: The University of Chicago Press, 1944. (Box 1)
    - "Orthodox Church and Soviet State." The Protestant (Feb. 1945) (Box 1)
    - "The Law of Nature: Some General Considerations." unpublished essay. (Labeled as a reprint of "The Law of Nature in Greco-Roman Thought." The Journal of Religion 25/2 (April 1945): 97-118., but differs substantially from article.) (Box 1)
    - "The Law of Nature in Greco-Roman Thought." The Journal of Religion 25/2 (April 1945): 97-118. (Box 1)
    - "What Kind of Religion Has a Place in Higher Education?" Journal of Bible and Religion 13/4 (Nov. 1945): 184-192. (Box 1)
    - "A Faith for Free Men." in Together We Advance. ed. S.H. Frichtman. Boston: Beacon Press, 1946. pp. 44-65. (typewritten copy w/note) (Box 1)
    - "God is Love." Sermon preached at the Meadville Theological Seminary, Nov. 7, 1947. (Box 1)
    - "Natural Religion and the 'Myth' of the Eighteenth Century." Harvard Divinity School Bulletin 16 (1951): 17-32. (Box 1)
    - "The Chief End of Man." Harvard Divinity School Bulletin 19 (1954): 39-47. (Box 1)
    - "The Liberal Christian Looks at Himself." Unpublished address given at an interdenominational forum in Washington, Mar. 6, 1955. (attached is a typed note from JLA to Max Stackhouse regarding this address.) (Box 1)
    - "The Liberal Christian Looks at Himself." Unpublished address given at an interdenominational forum in Washington, Mar. 6, 1955. (with annotations, missing pp. 4-8.) (Box 1)
    - "The Ages of Liberalism." Journal Of Religious Thought 14/2 (Spring/Summer 1957): 101-117. (Box 1)
    - "Changing Frontiers: Vanishing and Emerging." Unitarian Christian Supp. (Oct. 1957):. (Box 1)
    - The Uses Of Diversity (Convocation address, delivered at the Memorial Church 9/25/1957). Cambridge, MA: Harvard University, 1957. (Box 1)
    - "Taking Time Seriously." in Taking Time Seriously. Glencoe, Il.: The Free Press, 1957. pp. 11-20. (Box 1)
    - The Social Import Of The Professions (Address given at the Twenty-First Meeting of the American Association of Theological Schools, Boston University School of Theology, June 17-20, 1958) (Box 1)
    - "Contributions of Occidental Religions to Cultural Understanding." in Proceedings of the IXth International Congress for the History Of Religions, Tokyo and Kyoto, 1958. Tokyo: Maruzen, 1960. pp.†730-735. (Box 1)
    - "The Study of Christian Social Ethics at the Divinity School." Harvard Divinity Bulletin 26/3 (April 1962): 11-21. (Box 1)
    - We Wrestle Against Principalities and Powers. (Sermon at the Ordination of Dr. Hans Rosenwald, First Parish in Cambridge, 6/7/1964) Cambridge, MA: The First Parish Pulpit, 1964. (Box 1)
    - "Paul Johannes Tillich: Memorial Minute Adopted by the Faculty of Divinity, Harvard University, May 23, 1966." Harvard University Gazette 61/37 (June 4, 1966): (offprint) (Box 1)
    - "Hits Win Ball Games: The Creative Thrust of Conflict." Address delivered at the General Assembly of the Unitarian Universalist Association, Hollywood, Florida, May 17, 1966. In abbreviated form the address has been published in The Register-Leader (Boston) 148/7 (Midsummer 1966): 3-5. (Box 1)
    - "Exiles, Trapped Exiles, in the Welfare State." Sermon given in Rockefeller Chapel, University of Chicago, Aug. 21, 1966. (Box 1)
    - Thou Shalt Not Commit Adultery. Unpublished Manuscript, 1966. (Box 1)
    - "Music as a Means of Grace." The Crane Review 10/1 (Fall 1967): 42-45. (Box 1)
    - "Exiles, Trapped in the Welfare State." The Unitarian Christian 22 (Winter 1967): 3-9. (Box 1)
    - "Liberty and Law." Unpublished speech given at Loyola University, Montreal, as part of a week-long panel, July 1968. (Box 1)
    - "The pragmatic theory of meaning." Presidential address, American Society of Christians Ethics. Washington, D.C.: January 24, 1969. (Box 1)
    - "The Purpose of a Liberal Arts Education." Journal of the Liberal Ministry 9 (Spring 1969): 3-8. (Box 1)
    - "Civil Disobedience: Its Occasions and Limits." Reprinted from Political and Legal Obligation: Nomos XII; Edited by J. Roland Pennock and John W. Chapman; Published by Atherton Press, Inc. 1970. (Box 1)
    - "'The Protestant Ethic' With Fewer Tears." Reprinted from In the Name of Life. New York: Holt, Rinehart & Winston, Inc, 1971. (Box 1)
    - "Statement before the Board of Directors, Massachusetts Council of Churches, February 3, 1971." (unpublished) (Box 1)
    - "From Psyche to Society." Perkins Journal 26/1 (Fall 1972): 17-24. (Box 1)
    - "The lure of persuasion: some themes from Whitehead." The Unitarian Universalist Christian 30/4 (1975-76): 5-22. (Box 1)
    - The Unitarian Universalist Christian 32/1-2 (1977). (Box 1)
    - "The Politics of Culture in an Ameican Perspective." The Politics of Culture 1/1 (1978): 17-20. (Box 1)
    - The Unitarian Universalist Christian 48/3-4 (1993). (Box 1)
    - On Being Human—The Liberal Way. Boston: American Unitarian Association., No date (Box 1)
    - "The existentialist thesis in current Christian thought." (unpublished manuscript)., No date (Box 1)
    - "The politics of culture in an American perspective." (unpublished manuscript)., No date (Box 1)
    - "Bibliography of Writings by James Luther Adams." Baros-Johnson, Irene P., Engel, Ronald J., and Lauer, Richard T. Chicago: Meadville/Lombard, 1990. (Box 1)
  - Allen, L. Dean
    - Rise up, O Men of God: The Men and Religion Forward Movement and Promise Keepers, Macon Georgia: Mercer University Press, 2002. (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Frederick L.
    - An Analysis of the Gospel of John, With Notes. Prepared for the Rhode Island Committee of Pastors, 1905. (Box 2)
    - "The Finality of the Christian Religion, Part II." The Watchman (April 5, 1906): 9-11. (Box 2)
    - The Eternal and Universal Significance of the Cross. [no publication information]., 1908 (Box 2)
    - "Jesus on the Cross Representing Man to God." The Watchman (May 14, 1908). (Box 2)
    - "What the Church Says Through Its Scholars." The Watchman (February 24, 1910): 9-12. (Box 2)
    - What Must Massachusetts Baptists Do to Be Saved?: an address delivered before the annual meeting of the Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society, October 27, 1915. [no publication information]. (Box 2)
    - Historic Baptist Principles: an address at the Conference on Fundamentals, Buffalo, NY, June 21, 1920. [no publication information]. (Box 2)
    - The Stewardship of the Unspeakable Gift. New York: The General Board of Promotion of the Northern Baptist Convention, 1922. (Box 2)
    - Rich Harvests and Ominous Clouds: an address at the annual meeting of the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, held at Milwaukee, Wisconsin, May 29, 1924, being a Review of the work of the year 1923-1924. New York: The Society, 1924. (Box 2)
    - "The Great Commission." The Crozer Quarterly (January and April, 1926). (Box 2)
    - Why Foreign Missions?: an address at the annual meeting of the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, Chicago, June 3, 1927. New York: The Society, 1927. (Box 2)
    - "Balthasar Huebmaier." [no publication information]., 1927 (Box 2)
    - "The Huebmaier Celebration." [Letter to the editor, no publication information]., 1928 (Box 2)
    - The Finality of the Christian Religion as set forth in The Epistle to the Hebrews: a paper read before the Baptist Ministers' Conference of New York City, September 17, 1928. (Box 2)
    - Speech … at the Northern Baptist Convention in Denver, Colorado, June 19, 1929, on the report of the Committee on Conference with Other Religious Bodies, proposing closer relations with the Disciples. [no publication information]. (Box 2)
    - "Why the Drys Oppose 'Resubmission' of the Eighteenth Amendment." April 9, 1932. [no publication information]. (Box 2)
    - "What is the Gospel?" New York: American Baptist Home Mission Society, Department of Evangelism, no date. (Box 2)
    - "The Gospel of John: address on the twelfth chapter." Prepared for the Rhode Island Committee of Pastors, no date. (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Galusha
    - Notes on Homiletics. Boston: Rockwell & Churchill, 1872. (Box 2)
    - Pre-millenarianism. Chicago: G. E. Cole, Printers, 1890. (Box 2)
    - The Supreme End of Theological Schools. An address delivered before the Robinson Rhetorical Society, at the semi-centennial of the Rochester Theological Seminary, May 8, 1900. no publication information. (Box 2)
    - The Kingdom That Changed Rulers: preached at the twelfth annual convention of the Baptist Young People's Union of America in Providence, RI., July 13, 1902. s.l.: Printed by the Baptist Young People's Union of America. (Box 2)
    - Asterius, Bishop of Amasia. Ancient Sermons for Modern Times. Put into English from the Greek by GA and Edgar Johnson Goodspeed. New York: Pilgrim Press, 1904. (Box 2)
  - Arbuckle, Charles Nathaniel
    - "The Method and Aims of Religious Education." The Church School Bulletin (First Baptist Church, Newton Centre) 2 (1923). (Box 2)
    - "For Christ and the Truth." (A pageant to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the American Baptist Publication Society, February 25, 1924). (Box 2)
  - Andrews, Elisha Benjamin
    - Brief Institutes of Our Constitutional History, English and American. Providence, 1886. (Box 3)
    - "The Word Made Flesh (lesson for third quarter, July 5)." In History, Prophecy, and Gospel: expository sermons on the International Sunday-School Lessons for 1891, ed. EBA. Boston: Silver, Burdett & Co., 1891. (Box 3)
    - "Against Intemperance (lesson for second quarter, May 21)." In Gospel from Two Testaments: sermons on the International Sunday-School Lessons for 1893, ed. EBA. Providence: E. A. Johnson & Co., 1892. (Box 3)
    - "Redemption in Christ (lesson for fourth quarter, October 8)." In Gospel from Two Testaments: sermons on the International Sunday-School Lessons for 1893, ed. EBA. Providence: E. A. Johnson & Co., 1892. (Box 3)
  - Berkeley, James Percival
    - "The Challenge of Religious Education." The Church School Bulletin (First Baptist Church, Newton Centre) 3 (1924):3–8. (Box 4)
    - You Can Teach. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1941. (Box 4)
    - "Bible Study Commission, Part I: Studies in the Inner Life of the Christian." In The Baptist Young People's Union of the Maritime Provinces Hand Book of Program Material, 1941–42. The Union, [1941]. (Box 4)
    - "Professor James P. Berkeley number." Andover Newton Theological School Bulletin 41 (April 1949). (Box 4)
    - Knowing the Old Testament. Philadelphia: Juson Press, 1954. (Box 4)
    - Reading the Gospel of John. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1969., 1958 (Box 4)
    - Paul and the Philippians. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1969. (Box 4)
    - [untitled worship drama with voices and choir], no date (Box 4)
    - "The Use of the Bible in the Curriculum of Christian Education." [Document prepared for discussion in the Curriculum Committee of the Council of Christian Education of the Northern Baptist Convention.], no date (Box 4)
  - Billinsky, John Milton
    - "Cooperative Study of Juniors in Seven American Bapist Seminaries and Baptist Missionary Training Schools." 1951. [no publication information]. (Box 5)
    - "Cooperative Study of Juniors in Seven American Bapist Seminaries and Baptist Missionary Training Schools." 1952. [no publication information]. (Box 5)
    - ["Statement regarding clinical pastoral education."] Theological Education and Clinical Pastoral Training, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 5–9, 1959, Framingham, MA, iv. (Box 5)
    - "Objectives of clinical pastoral training." Clinical Pastoral Education, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 24–27, 1960, Framingham, MA, 1–29. (Box 5)
    - "The roles of the pastoral counselor." Andover Newton Quarterly 1 (November 1960): 5–21. (Box 5)
    - "Response to P.E. Johnson's Paper." In Levels of Clinical Pastoral Training, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 16–20, 1961, Framingham, MA. (Box 5)
    - "Integration of clinical pastoral education with theological education." In Theological Education and Clinical Pastoral Training, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 15–19, 1962, Craigville, MA, 28–37. (Box 5)
    - "Facing the merger question." In Clinical Pastoral Training's Contribution to Theology, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 15–17, 1963, Indianapolis, IN, 21–24. (Box 5)
    - "The roles of the pastoral counselor." In Supervision and Clinical Pastoral Training, Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference of Chaplain Supervisors, October 13–16, 1964, Chicago, IL, 1–29. (Box 5)
    - "Identity and power of the chaplain—faking it or facing it." In Addresses and Workshop Papers, American Protestant Hospital Association, College of Chaplains, 5–12. Chicago: The Association, 1973. (Box 5)
    - Guide to Comfort and Strength. Monks Memorial Chapel, Boston City Hospital, Boston, MA., no date (Box 5)
  - Brooks, Henry C.
    - "A philosophy of clinical pastoral education." Institute of Pastoral Care, Fall Conference, Chaplain supervisors. Clinical Pastoral Education (Framingham, MA: October 5–9, 1959): 112–117. (Box 5)
    - "Statement of clinical pastoral education." In Clinical Pastoral Education Conference, Chaplain Supervisors, (Framingham, MA: Institute of Pastoral Care, 1959): 7–8. (Box 5)
    - "Methods employed in clinical pastoral training." (In National Conference on Clinical Patoral Education, 7th. Trends in Clinical Pastoral Education: Objectives, Methods Standards: Proceedings Of The Seventh National Conference On Clinical Pastoral Education Washington, D.C., 1960.) (Box 5)
  - Brown, Charles Rufus
    - "The Life and Activity of Jeremiah." [Item is not identified, but seems to be an outline for a book on Jeremiah]. 1891. (Box 5)
    - "Do the Literary Postulates of Hexateuch Criticism Have Any Parallels in the Other Books of the Old Testament?" Andover Review 18 (September 1892). (Box 5)
    - The Book of the Prophet Jeremiah: A New and Critical Translation. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1906. (Box 5)
    - "The El-Tekkiyeh Inscriptions." American Journal of Archaeology 2nd Series 15 (1911): 523-532. (Box 5)
  - Brush, John Woolman
    - "God's Broken Things." First Baptist Herald 2/2 (April 1929): 3-4. (Box 6)
    - "Letters to the Editor." The Baptist World (1 October 1933): 232/ (Box 6)
    - "Bibliography: Church History." Andover Newton Theological School Bulletin 33/3 (April 1941): 15–17. (Box 6)
    - "Thomas Muenzer: Violent Mystic of the Reformation." Andover Newton Theological School Bulletin 33/4 (June 1941): 9–13. (Box 6)
    - "Listen to the Poets." Topic: The Quarterly for Young People's Meetings 2/2 (January–March 1942): 13–16. (Box 6)
    - "Address to the Graduating Class." Andover Newton Theological School Bulletin 35/4 (June 1943): 3–5. (Box 6)
    - "Poets of the Bible." Topic: The Quarterly for Young People's Meetings 3/4 (July–September 1943): 34–39. (Box 6)
    - "In Defense of the Otherworldly." The Crozer Quarterly XXI/3 (July 1944): 232–237. (Box 6)
    - "In Defense of the Otherworldly." Crozer Quarterly 21 (July 1944): 232 –237. (Box 7)
    - "Finding God Outdoors." Topic: The Quarterly for Young People's Meetings 4/4 (July–September 1944): 60–63. (Box 6)
    - "Into the New Year with Christ." Young People's Topic 5/1 (October, November, December 1944): 77–80. (Box 6)
    - "Bibliography: Church History." Andover Newton Theological School Bulletin 38/2 (February 1946): 14–17. (Box 6)
    - "Missions in Our Time: Bibliography." Bulletin of the General Thological Library XXXVIII/3 (April 1946). (Box 6)
    - "The liberty of prophesying." Crozer Quarterly 25 (July 1948): 216–223. (Box 6)
    - Appointment with History. Hartford, CT: Asylum Avenue Baptist Church, 1948. (Box 6)
    - "Agreement Hill." Stonington Tricentennial: Souvenir Program (6–27 August 1949): 9–12. (Box 6)
    - The March of the Christian Church. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1951. (Box 6)
    - "Two Meetings On Evangelism." The High Call (Winter 1950): 25–28. (Box 6)
    - "Talk Religion at Home." Hearthstone (February 1950): 14–15. (Box 6)
    - The March of the Christian Church. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1951. (Box 6)
    - "The Light that Makes a Difference." The Andover Newton Bulletin XLV/1 (October 1952): 19–21. (Box 6)
    - Forward Through the Darkness. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1952. (Box 6)
    - "The fire, not the ashes." Andover Newton Bulletin 46/1 (October 1953): 17–19. (Box 6)
    - "Where the Light Shines." Home (A.B.P.S.) (April–June 1954): 6–8. (Box 6)
    - The March of the Christian Church: Teacher's Text. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1956. (Box 6)
    - Forward Through the Darkness: Teacher's Text. Philadelphia: Judson Press, 1956. (Box 6)
    - "Baptists and Congregationalists." Andover Newton Bulletin 49 (April 1957): 27–33. (Box 6)
    - "Safeguard Those Church Records." Protestant Church Administration & Equipment (September 1957): 42–46. (Box 6)
    - "Three Frenchmen in Strasbourg and Later." Andover Newton Bulletin XLX/2 (October 1957): 3–12. (Box 6)
    - "Heirs of the Reformation." Baptist Leader (October 1958): 30–34. (Box 6)
    - Guide to Prayer. Andover Newton Waymarks, 1958. (Box 6)
    - "Recent Books in Church History." The Andover Newton Bulletin LI/2 (February 1959): 28–30. (Box 6)
    - "Bibliography for Church People: and Others Interested in Solid Reading and Study on Religious Subjects ." Bulletin of the General Theological Library LI/2 (February 1959): 3–7. (Box 6)
    - "Man in a cave." Christian Century 76 (November 25, 1959): 1371–1373. (Box 6)
    - "John Gill's Doctrine of the Church." In Baptist Concepts of the Church, ed. Winthrop S. Hudson, 53–70. Chicago: Judson Press, 1959. (Box 7)
    - "The imitation of Christ." Bulletin of Crozer Theological Seminary 52/2 (January 1960): 7–9, 6, 11. (Box 7)
    - "The Prayer Group: An Outline." In A Guide to Small Group Worship, ed. The Religious Life Committee, 14–15. Newton Centre, Massachusetts: Andover Newton Theological School, October 1960. (Box 7)
    - "The Dialect of Canaan." Andover Newton Quarterly 1 (November 1960): 35–42. (Box 7)
    - "This is My Discipleship." In This is My Discipleship, John W. Brush, William J. Keech, and Norman H. Maring, 5–16. The Judson Press, 1961. (Box 7)
    - Who's Who in Church History. Boston: Whittemore Associates, 1962. (Box 7)
    - "Does Your Teen-Ager Understand Protestantism?" Hearthstone: The Magazine for the Christian Home 14/8 (August 1962): 4–5, 30. (Box 7)
    - "1803–1820." Missions: American Baptist International Magazine 161/7 (September 1963): 16–17. (Box 7)
    - "Yoked in Fellowship: A Reminiscence of Andover Newton Theological School." Foundations: A Baptist Journal of History and Theology VI/4 (October 1963): 336–342. (Box 7)
    - "Listen, Mr. Littlefaith!: Is the Christian world mission now a useless, wasteful hangover from the Carey Judson era? Here is a reasoned answer to that persistent question" Missions: American Baptist International Magazine 162/9 (November 1964): 19–20. (Box 7)
    - Prayer and History. Newton Centre, MA, 1964. (Box 7)
    - Heritage of Faith and Freedom: A Short History of the First Baptist Church, Haverhill, MA. Groveland, MA: Boyd James Press, 1964. (Box 7)
    - Legacy of Faith: A Short History of the First Baptist Church of Boston. Groveland, MA: Boyd James Press, 1965. (Box 7)
    - "Christian Laughter." Frontiers… the growing edge of faith 4/4 (July–September 1966): 5–6. (Box 7)
    - "Writing Histories of Three New England Churches." Baptist History and Heritage: A Southern Batist Journal 2/1 (January 1967): 41–45. (Box 7)
    - "Barstow of Keene, N.H." Bulletin of the Congregational Library 19 (May 1968): 8 –12. (Box 7)
    - "Jolly old Saint Nicholas—Where did he come from?" Boston Herald Traveler Book Guide (21 December 1969): 6–7. (Box 7)
    - "A brief centennial history of the ministers' club of Boston." (unpublished manuscript, 11/20/1969). (Box 7)
    - Baptists in Massachusetts. Valley Forge, PA: Judson Press, 1970. (Box 7)
    - "From Rev. John Eliot Jr. to Rev. Zodhiates: A Summary of Religious Change 1660–1973." Newton Centennial 1873–1973 (1973): [pages no numbered]. (Box 7)
    - The Life of the Christian Church: Its Roots and Development, Boston: Whittemore Assoc., Inc., [no date]. (Box 7)
    - Belonging Is Not Enough, Boston: Whittemore Assoc., Inc., [no date]. (Box 7)
    - Foot-beats,, Boston: Whittemore Assoc., Inc., [no date]. (Box 7)
    - The Door: A Message to Persons Becoming Protestants, Boston: Whittemore Assoc., Inc., [no date]. (Box 7)
    - Grace is the Word, Boston: Whittemore Assoc., Inc., [no date]. (Box 7)
    - What Do You Read?, Newton: Andover Newton Theological School, [no date]. (Box 7)
    - "Speaking the Truth in Love." Adult Teacher 4/6 (June 1951): 15–17., no date (Box 7)
  - Burrows, Mark S.
    - Minding the spirit: the study of Christian spirituality. Eds: Dreyer, E.A. and M. Burrows, Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press, 2005. (Box 8)
  - Burton, Ernest DeWitt
    - Syntax of Moods and Tenses in the New Testament Greek. Boston, 1888. (Printed for private circulation) (Box 9)